Okay, so if you've got an access to the repo, you should see here there's some basic pre-requisites that I want to make sure you have in your environment
Basically, you should have get the latest node version of node and most importantly if you're using VS code the two
VS code extensions you want to use are
Volar and the TypeScript plugin view. So this is the
Volar extension and then the other one here
Technically could be optional, but I just want to make sure people install it and enable it just to make sure everything's working correctly
This is how you'll get a lot of your autocomplete error checking and all that stuff. So these are really critical without these it'll kind of be tricky
In addition, if you haven't downloaded or ready the view dev tools that could be useful tool for you as well as
When you're working with the
Application that will be building today so that you can find that basically under the Chrome extension store
As far as starting a new project with view and TypeScript
Most of us for who have done view before are familiar with the view CLI and basically the CLI tool to all the scaffold
Our projects together, but the important thing that I want to highlight is that view CLI is now in maintenance mode
Because it was using webpack and for those that don't know, VJS is kind of like the new like
Next-generation build tool that a lot of ecosystems are buying into and so this one the reasons view CLI is being
Deprecated is because we're moving basically revamping the architecture that powered view CLI with feet
So that you can get all the latest and greatest with that and so when you're starting a new project
You can you'll see that inside of the there is definitely a way for you to just use the
CLI here to just create a feet project and then just scaffold it with view and TypeScript and it does everything for you
But in case you didn't know we actually have another CLI that's basically going to be the successor to
The view CLI and that is create view so create view basically works as you would expect where you
Initialize a new view project it'll go through ask you to start up a couple of things as you can see it
Which asks you whether or not you want TypeScript j set x support you know where you want view router pinion all those things
And so what the project we'll be working on today is based on a scaffold that is built with the
Create view CLI so just so you know if you're ever starting a new one. This is kind of where it's recommended for you to keep an eye on
All right, so let's go ahead and open up the project. So if you go ahead and clone the repo
This is basically what you should be seeing
Inside of here you'll see that there's the basic read me in here where we'll go and update when we have
Bookmarks for the different branches as we go to the workshop
But then the main thing here is what we have inside of the app and that's what we'll be working with today
As you can see here, this is basically your standard view project
In fact, most of the client frameworks look like this now where you have your source directory with comes with all your assets
Components you'll see that I already have view router and pinion
Install the ready, so that's why you see the router folder and the source
And as well as the views which represent the different pages that will be moving towards
Otherwise
A couple of things that you might notice that's a little bit different is that you'll notice that all the files in here already labeled TypeScript and so
One of my recommendations when starting a new project even if you're not intending on using TypeScript is to just set it up with TypeScript anyways
And the reason I recommend that is because this is one last thing you have to worry about later on because
There's a magical configuration that's I've already set up in here
Which is that instead of your compiler options if you set it to allow JS true
It'll basically allow you to write vanilla JavaScript as you would even inside of so-called TypeScript files
So you'll see inside of here if you look at the constants
This is a constant file. It is technically a TypeScript file, but if you see everything in here standard JavaScript and
That's what I recommend on most view projects because after all at the end of the day
We want to teach people how to progressively migrate towards TypeScript and this is the best balance between the two because
Anyone who's done try to do a migration before is it's a lot to get the compiler working with all the built tools and everything
So that's why I say getting started just go ahead and opt into it
You can opt out with the TS config and then you can slowly kind of sprinkle it in as we go
And that's exactly what we'll be doing inside of this workshop
Let's run through the project as far as what we'll be working with today
So let me go ahead and open this up and then refresh
All right, so the project we'll be working on today is called to eat and so it's kind of a play on the to-do
MVC where instead of tracking all the things you want to do this is the track all the things that you want to eat
And so there's this is a the standard home page here with a little bit of a hero
And then you can go through we can see
We see all the restaurants that we want to try and then you see some basic properties that we have
We'll be able to create a new restaurant if we want and then we'll also be able to like so we can filter here for example
And then there are dishes that we want to you know track as far as like maybe something we want to cook or maybe you want to track specific dishes with restaurants
We have a lot of opportunity for playing creativity here and so that's something I want to really encourage when it comes to
Working on the exercises today is that I'll give you some basic guidance on the things we'll like main objectives that you want to accomplish
But the key thing here is to make sure that you go ahead and have fun with this because that's where a lot of the learning happens
And so if you find ways to like play around create custom types or whatnot
I encourage you to do that in the meantime before we move on let me go ahead and actually show you one more extension that I highly recommend and
That is text pastry
So if you haven't heard of this one before or yep text pastry
It's a really nifty plugin because one of the things I found when I'm working with playing around with data is
You want to custom ID and so normally we just randomly generate like you know what we just put one two three for five
But here for example, we say like cons again like this the do it to do this real quick
What we can do really easily is let's say I go ahead and just duplicate this a couple times
bump bump bump bump bump bump. Okay, here we go. We have three items right
So what I can do is if I put my cold cursor one two three and I type ID I can use text pastry
to actually
Where's it insert a custom UU ID and so that's like a nice little way for you to basically create some scaffold data with an
actual UID rather than accidentally creating a fake you know ID that's tracked in your view key later
That screws up animation text pastry is really cool. It does some other cool things as well
Actually just to make sure one other thing is that if you ever need to track anything so like a multi-line thing
So all you gotta do is you can select multiple lines and then text pastry can actually do counts from like zero to one and so little things like that
ABC so
Little
Hidden nugget to workflow efficiency, but
Highly recommend it for those if you don't have it already